Guide to the Eugenie V. Mielczarek papers, 1965-1997
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
Eugenie V. Mielczarek papers
1965-1997
C0059
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
13.5 linear feet (37 boxes)
This collection contains materials relating to the scientific and academic career of Eugenie V. Mielczarek in the area of physics, primarily at George Mason University.
Mielczarek, Eugenie Vorburger
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Eugenie Mielczarek in 1998.
Biographical Information
Eugenie Vorburger Mielczarek was the first woman physicist at George Mason University and served on several faculty committees. She has written on biophysics and on women in the sciences. Her publications include two books: 'Iron, Nature's Universal Element: Why People Need Iron and Animals Make Magnets,' coauthored with Sharon Bertsch McGrayne; and 'Biological Physics,' coedited with Elias Greenbaum and Robert S. Knox. Mielczarek passed away at the age of 86 on June 26, 2017.
Scope and Content
This collection contains materials relating to the scientific and academic career of Eugenie V. Mielczarek in the area of physics, primarily at George Mason University. Items include scientific data and research results, conference information, grant proposals, speaking engagements, presentations, correspondence, and publications. Prominent is information relating to national and local organizations of women scientists, including material about women scientists at GMU.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by subject.
Related Material
Special Collections Research Center also holds the.
Appraisal note
Documents related to hiring, human resources, student conduct, student grades,and personally identifiable information have been removed according to Library of Virginia records retention schedule.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
George Mason University. Dept. of Physics and Astronomy.
Persons:
Mielczarek, Eugenie Vorburger
Subjects:
Biomagnetism.; Biophysics.; Iron--Physiological effect.; Magnetoreception.
Contents List
- Personnel Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Microwave Proposal, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Thermal Conductivity Paper, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Research Papers, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Conference Papers, 1950s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Time Lecture, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Published Professional Papers, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Journal (Experiment), 1970s (Box 1, Folder 8)
- College of William and Mary Physics Department, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Department of Physics- Center for Statistical Mechanics and Thermodynamics, circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Kent Correspondence- Quadruple Splitting of Prophyen Compound, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Chemical Requests, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Personnel Correspondence, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Personnel Employment at Catholic University, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Office of Naval Research Grant, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Office of Research and Advanced Studies Grant, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Chemistry Notes, circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Office of Naval Research Proposal, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Research Proposal, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Solid State and Materials Research Program, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Chemical Clocks- A Set of Demonstrations, circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Master's Thesis Calculations, 1950s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Notebooks- notes and equations, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Notebook- notes and equations, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Notebook- notes and equations, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Notebooks- notes and equations, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Kennedy Bill- Women in Science, 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Chemical Clock, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Published Papers- Oscillation in Chemistry, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Notes, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Notes, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Azotobacter, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Azotobacter sample- first set of workbooks, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Virginia Institute for Scientific Research- Crystal Research, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Thermometry notebooks, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Thermal Conductivity notebook, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Thermal Conductivity Book IV, circa 1960s (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Thermal Conductivity notebook, circa 1960s (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Ultrasonic Attenuation in Solids Theory Book, circa 1960s (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Ultrasonic Attenuation in Solids, circa 1960s (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Magneto- Acoustic Resonance II, circa 1960s (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Liquid Semiconductors, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Notes, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Notes, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Binder 2 of Copper (Cu)-1, March 7-12, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Binder 2 of Copper (Cu)-2, March 7-12, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Copper II, March 25-26, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- National Institute of Health- Computational Book George Mason University, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Computation Book, 1980s-1990s (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Computation Notes, 978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Mossbauer Notebook, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Mossbauer Spectroscopy Run notebook, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- National Institute of Health Research Notebook, circa 1970s (Box 7, Folder 6)
- National Science Foundation Report Proposal for Research Investigation of the Transport of Iron Siderphone Across Cellular Membrane, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- National Science Foundation Annual Report, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Proposals (old), 1980s (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Contract Renewal- James Shea, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Report Draft, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Mielczarek Biography- Who's Who, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Letters and Agenda for Executive Committee Meeting, September 23, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- American Association of Physics Teachers- Chesapeake Section, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 4)
- National Science Foundation Supplemental Request, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- James Shea- Information, 1960s (Box 8, Folder 6)
- James Shea- Correspondence, 1960s (Box 8, Folder 7)
- James Shea- Testimony, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- National Science Foundation- Transport of Iron by Siderphone, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Proposals (old), circa 1970s (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Promotions Committee-1, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 1)
- James Shea- Final Submission, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- National Science Foundation Grant Budget Tally 1, 1987-1990 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- National Science Foundation Grant Budget Tally 2, 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- National Science Foundation Grant Award, 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Appointment- Chesapeake Section, 1960s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Grading Bloc, circa 1970s (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Personnel Picture Press Release, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Dowe, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- National Science Foundation Renewal- 1, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- National Science Foundation Renewal-2, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Faculty Salary Data, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Minority Report- Affirmative Action Faculty Salary, 1970s-1980s (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Affirmative Action Task Force, 1980s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Mossbauer Effect Selected Reprints, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Meeting of Women's Action Groups with President Dykstra, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- State Salary Study, 1970s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Labor Survey, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Journal de Physique, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Mossbauer Effect Data Index, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Lab Notebook, circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Personnel Action Form and Data Information, 1970s-1990s (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Committee on Status of Women, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- George Mason University- Volume 3, June 1980 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Biological Sample Preparation Book, May 1983 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Mossbauer- Israeli and German Experiments, 1970s (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Mossbauer Notebook, 1977-1979 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Pseudomans Angelnoso, circa 1960s (Box 12, Folder 5)
- National Institute of Health- George Mason University, May 1978-June 1980 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- National Institute of Health- George Mason University, September 1977-May 1978 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- American Physical Society Committee on the Status of Women, 1980-1991 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- American Physical Society Committee on the Status of Women, 1980-1991 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- American Physical Society Committee on the Status of Women in Physics, 1970s-1980s (Box 13, Folder 3)
- American Association of Physics Teachers, 1970s (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Salary Worksheet, 1978-1980 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- George Mason University Salary List, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Salary Equity, 1990s (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Salary Equity Study, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Bell Laboratories Harassment Report, 1980s (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Salary Equity Evaluation, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Submission of Report, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- George Mason University Salary Equity Study, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- A Salary Compensation Analysis of Full Time Instructional Faculty, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Salary Compensation Committee Report, 1980s (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Affirmative Action Plan, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Draft, 1980s (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Final Report of the Affirmative Action Task Force, June 1975 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Lab Notes, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Zarkin Zobilabotincky Reagent, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Theoretical Investigation of Ultrasonic Attention for Free Electrons in the Presence of a Magnetic Field, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Measurements of the Ultrasonic Attenuation in Copper, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Mossbauer Spectroscopy Chapter 2, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- AIP-US Steel Foundation Science Writing Award in Physics and Astronomy, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Chemical Clocks- Experimental and Theoretical Models of Nonlinear Behavior draft, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Chemical Clock-Page, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Graphs, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Chemical Clock-Critical Review, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Magnetoacoustic Absorption and the Fermi Surface in Potassium, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- United States Steel 1979 Writing Prize (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Research Materials, circa 1970s (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Oscillating Reaction Project, circa 1970s (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Chemical Clock- page, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Figure 4, circa 1970s (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Letter- Brent Rudy, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- AIP-US Steel Foundation Science Writing Award for Journalists, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- NBS 500- Analysis Paper, circa 1970s (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Letter from the Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Data and Graphs- Control Samples 57 FE Only, circa 1970s (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Data from Jack- His Voice Experiment 1970s (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Letter Transmitting Initial Consideration of Samples, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Oscillatory Magnetoacoustic Attenuation, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Department of Physics- Catholic University American MSA Research-2, circa 1960s (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Department of Physics- Catholic University American MSA Research 1, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Bio Met Revisions- old, circa 1970s (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Chemical Clocks, circa 1960s (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Chemical Oscillate, circa 1960s (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Requests for Copy of Papers, 1970s-1980s (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Roland, circa 1970s (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Science Program Group, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Senior Projects, circa 1970s (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Sex Discrimination Federal Regulation, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Summer Stipend, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Technical Illustrations, 1985-1987 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Traylor Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Science Writing Award, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Visiting Scientist Program, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Visiting Women Scientists Program, 1977-1979 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Visiting Scientists Program in Physics, 1963-1965 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Visiting Scientists Program in W.S., 1966 (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Visiting Scientists Program in Physics, 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 14)
- Visiting Scientists Program in Physics, 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 15)
- Visiting Scientists Program in Physics, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 16)
- Visiting Scientists Program- Elizabethtown, Pennsylvania, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 17)
- Visiting Scientists Program, 1968-1969 (Box 19, Folder 18)
- Virginia Academy of Science Speech, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Visiting Scientists Program, 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 2)
- American Physical Society- Cincinnati Meeting, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Visiting Scientist Program, 1970-1972 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Visiting Scientist Program Emmanuel College, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Virginia Academy of Science, 1980s (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Washington Women's Network, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- White Dabney, 1978-1979 (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Weingart Foundation, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Women's Career Day, 1970s (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Women's Achievement and Win, circa 1970s (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Joint Committee on Women in Science, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 12)
- Women's General, 1970s-1980s (Box 20, Folder 13)
- Women and Minorities in Science and Engineering, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 14)
- Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1970s (Box 20, Folder 15)
- Why a Women's College?/Why More Women Work at Traditional Male Jobs, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 16)
- Physicists Need to Help the Medi- Article, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 17)
- Virginia Academy of Science Speech, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 18)
- Women-Employment, 1960s-1990s (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Women in Science and Technology Conference, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Women in Science Mathematics- A Bibliography, circa 1980s (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Women in Physics, circa 1970s (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Bibliography, circa 1983 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Steve Cauffman Service Project, circa 1987 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Pyoverdine Journal of Biological Chemistry Paper, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Pyoverdine Paper- Draft Materials, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- National Science Foundation, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 9)
- Research Corporation, 1983-1984 (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Research Center Proposal, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Ramsay Correspondence, June 30, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 12)
- Queen's College Science Committee, 1983-1986 (Box 21, Folder 13)
- American Association of Physics Teachers, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 14)
- Risk, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 15)
- Random House, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 16)
- National Science Foundation- Women, 1983-1984 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- National Science Foundation- Research in Undergraduate Institutions Program, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Scanning Tunneling Microscope, October 15, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Research Support- Graduate Study Leave, 1989-1993 (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Rossini Travel and Reduced Load, 1989-1990 (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Rossini Travel and Reduced Load, 1989-1990 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Careers in Physics, 1960s (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Optical Measurement of the Zaikon- Zhabotinsky Reagent, 1972-1973 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Fractals and Nonlinear Dynamics in Biology and Chemistry, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Symposia Planning (Box 22, Folder 10)
- Careers in Physics, 1963-1964 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- PEER- Guide to Ending Sex Bias in Your Schools, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Summer Sessions, 1979-1993 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- TiFe Paper, circa 1970s (Box 23, Folder 4)
- The Isomer Shift in FeA1- San Diego Paper, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 5)
- San Diego Paper Requests, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Publications Montreal Washington Talks, 1960-1961 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- A Magneto- Acoustic Determination of the Fermi Surface of Potassium, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Ultrasonic Attenuation in Potassium at 4.2 Kelvin, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Office of Naval Research Paper, October 1961 (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Measurements of the Ultrasonic Attenuation in Copper, July 1962 (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Numerical Evaluation of the Ultrasonic Attenuation in Metals as a Function of the Magnetic Field, October 1962 (Box 23, Folder 12)
- Visiting Scientists Program, 1990-1992 (Box 23, Folder 13)
- Visiting Fellow, 1989-1990 (Box 23, Folder 14)
- Physical Review Papers- Mielczarek and Winfree, 1974-1975 (Box 23, Folder 15)
- Physical Review Papers- Mielczarek and Winfree, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 16)
- National Institute for the Environment, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 17)
- Nuclear Regulation Commission, 1993-1995 (Box 23, Folder 18)
- Travel, 1987-1988 (Box 23, Folder 19)
- The Determination of the Resistivity Ratio of Potassium by the Eddy-Current[...]John C. Edwards, May 1965 (Box 23, Folder 20)
- Institute, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- In-House, circa 1990s (Box 24, Folder 2)
- The American Physical Society, 1982-1983 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- General Culture Subcommittee, 1960s-1980s (Box 24, Folder 4)
- High Tech Consultants, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Doctor of Arts in Education, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Affirmative Action Task Force Report, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Maria Goeppert- Mayer Award Recipient Dr. Ida Lee, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 8)
- Ways of Knowing Course, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 9)
- Library, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 10)
- Machinists Applicants, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 11)
- Liquid Nitrogen, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 12)
- National Science Foundation Proposal Reading, October 1994 (Box 24, Folder 13)
- Space, Physics Department- Space and Personnel Requirements, circa 1970s (Box 24, Folder 14)
- The American Physical Society and American Association of Physics Teachers, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 15)
- Committee on Status of Women in Physics- The American Physical Society, 1980s-1990s (Box 24, Folder 16)
- Holt, Rhinehart, and Winston, 1983-1987 (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Howard University Seminar, 1983-1984 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- International Conference on Bioinorganic Chemistry, July 1999 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Herzfeld, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Application Blank Professional, 1979-1981 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Gordon Conference, 1959-1964 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Gordon Conference, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Gordon Conference, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 8)
- GENEX, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Grant Possibilities, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 10)
- Successful German Study Leave Application, 1980-1981 (Box 25, Folder 11)
- Paul Gaddis, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 12)
- FAX- Spectr EPR with Reference, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 13)
- Faculty Evaluation, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 14)
- Foundation Application, 1977-1980 (Box 25, Folder 15)
- Faculty Leave Application Study, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 16)
- Faculty Leave Application Study, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 17)
- EXXON, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 18)
- Joyce Evans, 1978-1983 (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Distinguished Faculty Award, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Dr. M. Dresselhaus, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Federation of Organization of Professional Women, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Congressman day, 1991-1992 (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Corporation for Public Broadcasting, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 7)
- McArdle Correspondence, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 8)
- Department of Health and Human Services, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 9)
- Intergovernmental Personnel Act, June 1971 (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Navy-Summer, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 11)
- Department of Education- National Science Foundation- Report to President, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 12)
- National Sciences Resource Center, 1985-1986 (Box 26, Folder 13)
- New Horizons Proposal, circa 1980s (Box 26, Folder 14)
- Newell, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 15)
- National Institute for the Environment, 1991-1995 (Box 26, Folder 16)
- National Public Radio, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 17)
- Jeffres Trust Proposal 1, 1981-1983 (Box 26, Folder 18)
- Kyoto- Funding Request and Trip Report, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 19)
- Equal Rights Amendment, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 20)
- Jackett Correspondence, March 19, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Request for Reprints of Articles, 1975-1979 (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Old Dominion University, circa 1991 (Box 27, Folder 3)
- National Science Foundation Referee, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 4)
- Travel Grant Application, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 5)
- National Science Foundation Science Faculty Fellowship, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 6)
- National Science Foundation Account, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 7)
- National Science Foundation Proposal, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 8)
- National Institute of Health Minority Research and Training Programs, 1980 (Box 27, Folder 9)
- National Science Foundation Research Equipment Proposed, 1979-1981 (Box 27, Folder 10)
- National Institute of Health/National Science Foundation Proposal, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 11)
- National Science Foundation, circa 1980s (Box 27, Folder 12)
- Filling Vacant Physics Department-Chair, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 1)
- Chair Evaluation Committee, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 2)
- Equipment Trust Fund, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 3)
- Equipment Request- Department Chair, circa 1990s (Box 28, Folder 4)
- Equipment Budget Committee, November 6, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 5)
- Athletics Council- George Mason University, 1995 (Box 28, Folder 6)
- Correspondence from Minas Kafatos, Chair of Physics Department, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 7)
- Machinist Position, 1986-1988 (Box 28, Folder 8)
- 10/39ths Rule, July 22, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 9)
- National Collegiate Athletics Association Handbook, 1993-1994 (Box 28, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1969-1990 (Box 28, Folder 11)
- Shared Research Instrumental Faculty, 1988-1989 (Box 28, Folder 12)
- University Research Grants Proposal, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 13)
- Office Space, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 14)
- Al Schindler, 1984-1991 (Box 29, Folder 1)
- Science Shop 1 of 2, 1989-1991 (Box 29, Folder 2)
- Science Shop 2 of 2, 1989-1991 (Box 29, Folder 3)
- Career Night, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 4)
- Salary Compensation Review Committee 1, 1982-1984 (Box 29, Folder 5)
- Salary Compensation Review Committee 2, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 6)
- State Equipment Committee 1, 1983-1985 (Box 29, Folder 7)
- State Equipment Committee 2, 1986-1987 (Box 29, Folder 8)
- University Research Grant Program, 1974-1975 (Box 29, Folder 9)
- Sigma Pi Sigma, circa 1970s (Box 29, Folder 10)
- Sigma Xi Local Chapter Files, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 11)
- Sigma Xi Personal, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 12)
- Shop Facility, 1966-1967 (Box 29, Folder 13)
- CAS Committee of Dept. Chair on Sponsored Research, April 3, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 14)
- Sigma Xi Chapter- George Mason College National, 1970-1972 (Box 29, Folder 15)
- Sigma Xi Chapter- National 1, 1960, 1970-1971 (Box 30, Folder 1)
- George Mason University- History, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 2)
- George Mason Today, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Department Memo's, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 4)
- CIT Internship Research Program 1 of 2, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 5)
- CIT Internship Research Program 2 of 2, 1984 (Box 30, Folder 6)
- 25 Year Service Certificate, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 7)
- Faculty Salary Schedule, 1973-1979 (Box 30, Folder 8)
- Hoyte-Mielczarek Papers, 1964-1965 (Box 30, Folder 9)
- Chemical, Biological, and Physical Clocks-Oscillation, 1960s (Box 31, Folder 1)
- The Thermal Conductivity of Inrium Antimonide, circa 1960s (Box 31, Folder 2)
- Mossbauer Spectroscopy of the Macromolecular System Paracoccus Deitrificans and Ferriparabactin, circa 1970s (Box 31, Folder 3)
- Book Reviews, 1967-1974 (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Chemical Clocks, etc., 1970 (Box 31, Folder 5)
- Carbon, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 6)
- Lab/Research/Visit Notes, 1970s (Box 31, Folder 7)
- Measurements of the Ultrasonic Attenuation in Copper, July 1962 (Box 31, Folder 8)
- Chemical Clock, 1980-1983 (Box 32, Folder 1)
- Letter (Division of Theoretical Chemistry), September 30, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Research Grant Finance, 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 3)
- Spectrophotometer Instruments, circa 1960s (Box 32, Folder 4)
- American Chemical Society Meeting, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 5)
- Magnetoacoustic Absorption and Fermi Surface in the Alkali Metal, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 6)
- Russian (Articles), 1964-1965 (Box 32, Folder 7)
- Papers and Notes, circa 1970s (Box 32, Folder 8)
- Application Vice-Provost, 1989 (Box 32, Folder 9)